

Vancouver, BC, Canada

(+1) 778-223-3274 tueboesen 🖸 Tue Boesen ▼ Tue.Boesen@protonmail.com

Scientific Focus

My main scientific focus areas are currently: machine learning and protein folding. More specifically, within machine learning, I have worked extensively with equivariant and graph-based networks, as well as transfer and selfsupervised learning. The goal of my work in machine learning has always been to fundamentally understand how neural networks work, which I believe is best done by connecting them with well-established areas of mathematics. Parts of this work lead to mimetic neural networks, and constrained neural networks, both of which are novel ideas in machine learning and has lead to a deeper understanding of how I think about neural networks.

Education

Aarhus University Denmark

Ph.D. in Geophysics 2015 - 2018

• Thesis: Numerical methods for electromagnetic geophysics beyond 1D

Aarhus University Denmark

M.S. IN THEORETICAL PHYSICS 2010 - 2011

· Thesis: Foundation for a parallel time-dependent density functional theory simulator in a spherical harmonic basis using the exact exchange energy functional

Aarhus University Denmark

B.S. IN PHYSICS 2006 - 2010

· Thesis: Feynmans Pathintegral i 1 dimension med fokus på sinusbaner (Feynman's path integral in 1 dimension with focus on sinusoidal trajectories)

Experience

Proteic Bioscience Inc. Vancouver, Canada

MACHINE LEARNING CONSULTANT Jan 2022 - June 2022

- · Developed and trained equivariant and mimetic neural networks for energy and force predictions for biomolecular systems.
- Developed a parallel framework for protein design using PyRosetta.

University of Bristish Columbia (UBC)

Vancouver, Canada POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH FELLOW IN MACHINE LEARNING May 2019 - Aug 2021

- Developed methods for applying constraints in high-dimensional space to smoothly constrain/guide a neural network.
- · Published mimetic neural networks for protein design and folding.
- · Developed self-supervised conditional probability neural networks for protein folding.
- Developed a semi-supervised active learning algorithm.

Computational Geoscience Inc.

Vancouver, Canada Al Research Scientist May 2019 - Aug 2020

· Published novel graph-based semi-supervised learning methods applied to seismic data.

HydroGeophysics Group at Aarhus University

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Aug 2017 - Apr 2017

Open-sourced a sparse iterative parallel linear solver based on my research during my Ph.D.

• Open-sourced an OpenMP parallelization framework developed during my Ph.D.

Danske Bank Copenhagen, Denmark

ANALYST, GRADUATE POSITION

· Worked in customer insight creating forecast models.

HydroGeophysics Group at Aarhus University

SCIENTIFIC PROGRAMMING CONSULTANT

• Created SPIA in Pascal, an application for ground-based electromagnetic measurements.

Aarhus, Denmark

Sep 2013 - Apr 2014

Aarhus, Denmark

Mar 2013 - Sep 2013

Publications

MAY 19, 2022 TUE J. BOESEN · CURRICULUM VITAE

IN PREPARATION

A-optimal active learning Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber

arXiv preprint arXiv:2110.09585 (2022). 2022

Constrained neural networks Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber

(2022). 2022

JOURNAL ARTICLES

Mimetic neural networks: a unified framework for protein design and folding Moshe Eliasof, Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, Chen Keasar, Eran Treister

Frontiers in Bioinformatics 2 (2022). 2022

Data-driven semi-supervised clustering for oil prediction

Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, G Michael Hoversten

Computers & Geosciences 148 (2021) p. 104684. Pergamon, 2021

An efficient 2D inversion scheme for airborne frequency-domain data

Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Anders Vest Christiansen, Gianluca Fiandaca, Casper Kirkegaard, Andreas Aspmo Pfaffhuber, Malte Vöge *Geophysics* 83.4 (2018) E189–E201. Society of Exploration Geophysicists and American Association of Petroleum ..., 2018

A parallel computing thin-sheet inversion algorithm for airborne time-domain data utilising a variable overburden

Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Anders Vest Christiansen, Gianluca Fiandaca, Cyril Schamper

Geophysical Prospecting 66.7 (2018) pp. 1402-1414. European Association of Geoscientists & Engineers, 2018

A review of airborne electromagnetic methods with focus on geotechnical and hydrological applications from 2007 to 2017 Esben Auken, Tue Boesen, Anders V Christiansen

Advances in geophysics 58 (2017) pp. 47–93. Elsevier, 2017

CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

Semi-supervised clustering for oil prospectivity

Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, G Michael Hoversten

ICLR AI for Earth Sciences workshop, 2020

Efficient 2D hybrid inversion of airborne frequency domain data

E Auken, T Boesen, AVC Christiansen, GF Fiandaca, AA Pfaffhuber, MV Vöge

Second European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2017

2D FEM inversion with a moving footprint and a hybrid 1D and 2D forward and derivative implementation

Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Malte Vöge, Casper Kirkegaard, Kristoffer Rønne Andersen, Andreas Aspmo Pfaffhuber, Anders Vest Christiansen

AGU Fall Meeting Abstracts, 2016

Rapid inversion of large airborne AEM data datasets utilizing massively parallel co-processors

C Kirkegaard, K Andersen, AV Christiansen, E Auken, T Boesen

First European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2015

Utilizing massively parallel co-processors in the AarhusInv 1D forward and inverse AEM modelling code

Casper Kirkegaard, Kristoffer Andersen, Tue Boesen, Anders V Christiansen, Esben Auken, Gianluca Fiandaca

ASEG Extended Abstracts, 2015

2.5D inversion of sea ice thickness from helicopter EM data

M Vöge, A Pfaffhuber, E Auken, C Kirkegaard, T Boesen, S Hendricks, P Hunkeler

First European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2015

Skills_

Platforms Windows, Linux Ubuntu, AWS

Programming Python, Pytorch, LaTeX, Git, Matlab, Fortran, Julia, Delphi/Pascal, OpenMp, MPI

Languages Danish, English

Teaching and supervision

TeachingAarhus University, Denmark

INSTRUCTOR 2009-2017

- Calculus.
- · Electric and Electromagnetic methods.
- Data processing and interpretation for groundwater mapping.
- · Geophysical methods.
- · Hydrogeophysical field course (twice).

May 19, 2022 Tue J. Boesen · Curriculum Vitae

SupervisionUBC, CanadaCo-Supervisor2020

• Jingrong Lin – Ph.D. student in geophysics.

May 19, 2022 Tue J. Boesen · Curriculum Vitae 3